Navabharath Bandi

Bellevue, Washington, United States



navabharath.bandi@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/navabharath-bandi

Summary

Experienced Data Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Databases, Data Warehousing, Azure Data Factory, and C#. Strong information technology professional graduated from Koneru Lakshmaiah College of Engineering.

Experience

Lead Data Engineer

Accenture

Oct 2017 - Present (3 years 7 months +)

- Lead the team to create and maintain data pipeline architecture for windows product group.
- Built the Big data pipelines required for optimal extraction, transformation, and loading of data from a wide variety of data sources using Cosmos, SCOPE, Xflow, SQL, Kusto.
- Developed tools and solutions using Azure including Azure Storage, Azure Data Factory, Azure Automation.
- Built analytics tools that utilize the data pipeline to provide actionable insights into App usage, app reliability, app flighting, and other key business performance metrics.
- Identified and implemented internal process improvements: automating manual processes, optimizing data delivery, re-designing data pipelines for greater scalability.
- Work with stakeholders including app owners, Program managers to assist with adhoc reporting, datarelated technical issues and support their new data needs.
- Implemented NGP guidelines to ensure expiry of data streams.
- Work with App owners and data stream owners to deliver actionable reports for new apps created.

Lead Automation Engineer

Accenture

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017 (9 months)

- Managed a team of 3 developers to deliver dashboard for Microsoft Treasury Application health and infrastructure health.
- Built Power BI dashboard with data collected from Azure Management Suite, Azure Log Analytics and using Azure automation including runbooks, webhooks.
- Review Peer Code using Microsoft Code Flow Tool and Visual Studio Team Service (VSTS) Pull requests.

> SQL Server DBA

Accenture

Mar 2014 - Dec 2016 (2 years 10 months)

• Experience in implementing different types SQL Server High Availability(HA/DR) techniques Replication, Mirroring, Log shipping, clustering and Always On Solutions.

- Troubleshoot performance problems like blocking, deadlocks, CPU, Memory, I/O bottlenecks with T-SQL queries, DBCC commands, DMVs, Perfmon, Profiler trace, Trace flags.
- Upgraded/Migrated SQL 2008 to SQL 2012, 2014 and SQL 2012 instance to SQL 2016.
- Applying Service packs, Cumulative Updates(CU) to keep the environments up to date.
- Expertise in DBA automation tasks using PowerShell along with T-SQL scripting.
- Expertise in Performance Tuning and Optimization (PTO) of Stored procedures, Complex T-SQL queries involving multiple joins, views by the use the Query plans, with Database Tuning advisor(DTA) and Index tuning wizard.
- Creating indexes Clustered, Non-clustered, on tables to improve the performance and dropping the unnecessary indexes.
- Expertise in performing administrative tasks: Designing Database, configuring Instance level settings, Memory settings and tempdb settings.
- Expertise in database file management, backup/restore, import/export, BCP utility, security management, DBCC, indexing, partitioning.
- Understands business requirements and design backup strategies (Full, Differential, Log backups) for the databases in Production environment to meet RPO and RTO.
- Refreshing DEV/UAT environments with production backups on daily or weekly basis as per the requirement.
- Knowledge of data warehouse concepts and creation of Power BI dashboard reports.
- Granting access to users through Windows Security Groups/SQL logins and assigning permissions through Standard Database roles or custom roles.
- Installing and configuring SSIS, SSAS, and SSRS services.

Senior Software Engineer

Accenture

Aug 2006 - Feb 2014 (7 years 7 months)

- Worked as System Engineer building infrastructure and deploying code every quarter
- Acquire infrastructure, build SQL servers, and web servers with necessary tools.
- Deploy code bits to pre-production environments like DEV, DIT and SIT.
- Coordinate with stakeholders including Development, build and test teams for the deployment of changes to test and rest of pre-production environments.
- Prepare and review rollback plans for quarterly deployments.
- Deploy and track new sequence of SQL configuration for each quarterly Deployment.
- Document the application knowledge and act as Technical SME to resolve common issues quickly.

Education



Acharya Nagarjuna University

Bachelor's degree

Skills

Microsoft SQL Server • SQL • Oracle • PL/SQL • Requirements Analysis • Agile Methodologies • Databases • SDLC • Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) • Data Engineering